in this video I'm going to demonstrate
some of the structural formatting tools
that you can use to enhance the meaning
and appearance of your presentation as
you can see the presentation that I have
on screen at the moment contains four
slides and there is no real definition
to the layout and the different sections
within each of the slate other than
having two images on the title flight so
when you're creating a presentation the
first thing you need to do is to make
sure that you select the right layout
for the slate that you're going to
include the content in so for example on
slide 1 this is a title 8 so if I just
click on that go to the Home tab and
then select a slightly out button I can
see that that is a title flayed for the
second one I have used here to contents
laid for the third slate it is a title
and content and for the fourth late
again it is a title and content so it is
important that you try and select the
correct layout for the information that
you need to include however it may be a
Kia site at a later point in the design
and development of your presentation
that you wish to change the slide layout
so for example on slide 3 at the moment
I have some information in here that may
be enhanced by the inclusion of earshot
so at this point what I'd need to do is
to change the actual layout of the slate
so now that I've got the slate
highlighted if I go up to the the layout
and then selected to content that will
automatically change so as you can see
it has compressed the information that
was already on the suede to the left
which that will then allow me to add the
different type of information to the
right so I could then select chart or a
table or some other type of information
and I thought to this slide I'll just
undo that there also may be occasions
where you may need to change the slate
order so when you're doing a
presentation you may think that slate 3
would be better a slate for slide 5 a
slate 6 and so on and so forth it's
quite straightforward within PowerPoint
to change the order of the slate all you
would need to do is as an example I'll
select it's late
and I want to change that so we'll
change places with slate three just
click and hold and then drag back down
and again if I wanted to chi and slate
for two slate three just click and hold
and drag it to where I wish it to be I
can then change them back and I have the
original order presented again as you
can see the the slides at the moment are
quite clean I have a white background as
text there but there is no definition
the information hasn't been broken up in
any way one of the other tools that you
can use is you can break each section
down so for example I'm going to use the
business course later demonstrate this
so I have the title section here so I
click on the title and the box appears
around it so I can then add a border to
that and I'm just going to select it a
plane back border and again for the
information to the left of the shot I
will select a border and for the chart
I'll do exactly the same and select a
border around the chart so as you can
see that there's no started to define
the information within this late I can
also tear that one step further and if I
highlight that I can actually add a fill
so I can select a color to fill the
background that's quite dramatic and
I'll go fast like shit there again I
could do this seeing sheered so the last
she had selected will automatically be
the one by default that you can select
for beginning drop down but I'll stick
with the sheered that I went with but
for the chart all I want to do is to
feign that by me and make the border
thick up so again the border was quite
thin so I can select weird and then I
can put I think I border around a chart
so as you can see that is slowly brought
in an information of so each section has
got its own defined area when creating
presentations there may also be
occasions where you need to hide certain
slides so for example it could be a
presentation that has been presented to
members of the staff and also
or monitors within an organization but
rather than have two different
presentations you've created one that
has additional information in for the
managers and when you present that to
the staff you need to make sure that the
a console slates so quite simply you can
hide the slides within the presentation
and to do that all you would do is
highlight the slate that you wish to
hide
right-click and then select hide slate
so when that was presented slate - as it
has a strikethrough there you would see
that that would not be displayed so with
and the presentation will go slate one
and then jump straight to slate three in
slate four and then when you decide that
you need to present that with all of the
slate Shawn you would simply right click
again and select hide slate and that
will take the strikethrough are we from
the number so in the presentation it
will go one two three and four with no
slates omitted as with would you also
have the opportunity to use headers and
footers and within PowerPoint to access
the hair doesn't footage you would
simply go to the insert tab and then
select hedoesn't foot us and it may be a
kiss that you wish to put the deer and
time in and how that updated
automatically or could be fixed with our
select date and time so whenever the
presentation is displayed and what
automatically changed the date to that
did that it was presented or you could
have it fixed so if you wanted to have
it fix or displayed the deer when the
presentation was created you would
select that option you can also select
slide number and if you look along the
right in the preview pane a junior
exactly where that information would be
and additionally you may also wish to
have the footer active so that could be
a kiss of you maybe need to put the the
company name in there or the author of
the presentation so far select that now
I have the option to either select it so
it doesn't show on the tail or slate but
I want to issue on every slate and I can
apply that but it will only apply it to
that one slate alternatively you can
select apply to wall and that will apply
that to every slide in the presentation
so if I select that now as you can see
it has applied that to each of the four
slate
primarily more slides within a
presentation or in landscape format and
most presentations are presented in
landscape format however there may be
occasions where you need to change it to
portrait format now within portrait
format one of the things you have to be
aware of is that when you change once
later portrait on late word where you
could have one page in landscape one
page in poetry at another page in
landscape within PowerPoint if you
change the orientation of one slate it
will change the orientation of all the
slates so just to demonstrate that if I
have the tie off late selected and then
I need to go to the design tab and on
the design tab select the slate size and
at the moment you've got stand at a
white screen but you would need this to
their custom slate size and from there
you would need to select portrait so if
I take a portrait and the talk here you
got two options so you can either
maximize the information or insure off
it if you select maximize it will
basically change the page orientation
thought the information within launched
in so if I do that now select maximize
and then select that as you can see that
isn't really fit for Paris because it's
changed the slides to portrait but the
information is still in landscape so if
I just undo that and again go back to
the slate size custom slate fit select
portrait select okey about this time I
select and Shore fit as you can see that
is then ensure that the information does
fit on the slate